<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Leo Balduf</title>
    <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Leo Balduf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 20:47:43 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://leobalduf.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch005</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 20:47:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch005/</guid>
      <description>Name: sketch005
Year: 2018
Description:
This series uses a noise field to orient and displace triangles.
When scaled correctly and time is applied, the result is a wave-like animation in real-time.
The images are frames of the animation, which try to capture the lifelike movements.
The technique is explored on neutral, grid-like setups as well as settings in which the triangles are attracted to, or repelled by, some part of the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch004</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 20:46:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch004/</guid>
      <description>Name: sketch004
Year: 2018
Description:
This was originally a poster for a birthday party of friends.
The image contains a collectino of mostly German words connected to the party.
It was later repurposed for public display by removing any identifying information from the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch003</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 20:45:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch003/</guid>
      <description>Name: sketch003
Year: 2018
Description:
This series started as a visualization of the CS-version of a tree.
Our trees have one root at the top, a number of branches in the middle, and finally leaves on the tips of branches.
Trees are generated randomly and represented using text.
(Many of the outputs are useless - they grow out of the frame, grow in a loop-like fashion back down to the root, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch002</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 20:44:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch002/</guid>
      <description>Name: sketch002
Year: 2018
Description:
This series explores excessive post-processing of 3D models to the point of no recognition.
The underlying model consists of randomly moving and rotating cubes in 3D space.
The model is first projected onto a 2D plane and then repeatedly rearranged, displaced, and mirrored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch001</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 20:43:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/sketch001/</guid>
      <description>Name: sketch001
Year: 2018
Description:
This series was created using a rule-based approach.
A number of small circles are drawn in random locations of the image.
These circles then grow larger until any two of them touch.
Of the two, one is eliminated through random choice.
The survivor continues to grow larger, whereas the eliminated restarts as a small circle in a new random location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LineReplica</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/linereplica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 20:44:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/linereplica/</guid>
      <description>Name: lineReplica
Year: 2017?
Description:
This series is an experiment about approximating images using geometric primitives, mostly lines.
The thing about it is that the program brute-forced the approximation by adding one line every frame, selecting from ~50 lines, seeing which one got the working image closest to the original.
Because of that, I could only run it on very low-resolution images, but it produces vector images.
If I then scale those up again, you see interesting effects which were not present in the original.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive</title>
      <link>https://leobalduf.com/projects/recursive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 20:43:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobalduf.com/projects/recursive/</guid>
      <description>Name: recursive
Year: 2016
Description:
This series explores the concept of recursion in computer programming, applied to line art.
The images were produced using only triangles, which are drawn inside each other recursively.
Even though they are drawn in 2D, the images exhibit an illusion of three dimensional structures when viewed from a distance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>